Guide to the Hans Baron Papers, 1867-2018 RL.00081
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Hans Baron papers
1867-2018 and undated
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Baron, Hans, 1900-
RL.00081
41.3 Linear Feet 88 boxes approximately 49,000 items
Hans Baron was a reknowned German-born historian and scholar of Italian Renaissance history and literature who emigrated from Germany in 1933. Collection includes research notes, writings, and drafts, primarily concerning the Italian Renaissance, humanism, medieval and renaissance politics, Petrarch, Machiavelli, and related topics. There are also materials regarding his most significant monographs, especially for In Search of Florentine Civic Humanism: Essays on the Transition from Medieval to Modern Thought. Papers include writings and correspondence to and from other scholars, including Ron Witt, William Bouwsma, Gene Brucker, and Paul Oskar Kristeller. The main collection has received basic processing. There are also later additions that have not been arranged: these include unsorted research and travel notes, writings, clippings, memorabilia, and correspondence. Some of these materials are related to his emigration from Germany to the United States as a Jewish refugee, and his subsequent teaching and research appointments.
49,800 Items
Access Restrictions
Collection is open for research.
Provenance
The Hans Baron Papers were received by the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library as a gift, 1994-1995, 2002, 2008, 2012, 2015, 2016, and 2017.
Biographical Note
Hans Baron was an influential German-born historian and scholar of Italian Renaissance history and literature. He emigrated from Germany in 1933.
Collection Overview
Hans Baron was a reknowned German-born historian and scholar of Italian Renaissance history and literature who emigrated from Germany in 1933. Collection includes research notes, writings, and drafts, primarily concerning the Italian Renaissance, humanism, medieval and renaissance politics, Petrarch, Machiavelli, and related topics. There are also materials regarding his most significant monographs, especially for In Search of Florentine Civic Humanism: Essays on the Transition from Medieval to Modern Thought. Papers include writings and correspondence to and from other scholars, including Ron Witt, William Bouwsma, Gene Brucker, and Paul Oskar Kristeller. The main collection has received basic processing. There are also later additions that have not been arranged: these include unsorted research and travel notes, writings, clippings, memorabilia, and correspondence. Some of these materials are related to his emigration from Germany to the United States as a Jewish refugee, and his subsequent teaching and research appointments.
Addition (02-265)(200 items, 0.4 lin. ft.; dated 1928-1971 and undated) contains research notes and materials relating to Francesco da Fiano, a 15th century Italian humanist. Also includes a packet of correspondence between Gene Brucker and Baron (1961-1971).
Addition (08-144)(45 items, .1 lin. ft.; dated 1971-1988) primarily contains correspondence between Baron and Ronald Witt (Duke University) regarding their publications and research, including grants for release time and negotiations with publishers; their agreements and disagreements regarding their area of specialization; and the problems associated with teaching at the college level in their specialty. Includes a few addendums to letters written by Baron's wife, Edith, as well as two letters to Witt from other sources. A few of the letters are missing pages.
Addition (2012-112) (0.8 lin. ft., 600 items) includes notes and edited drafts related to Hans Baron's work on Leonardo Bruni.
Addition (2015-0108) (2.0 lin. ft.) includes academic and personal correspondence, as well as other research and teaching materials, offficial emigration documents, travel notes, with a few memorabilia, and clippings, largely dating from the mid-1920s-1960s.
Addition (2017-0111) (1.0 lin. ft.) includes manuscript drafts, correspondence, and reproductions regarding Poggio Florentini.
College teachers -- Correspondence; Humanism -- Italy; Italy -- History -- 1268-1492; Italian literature -- 15th century -- History and criticism; Italian poetry -- 15th century -- History and criticism; Renaissance -- Italy; Renaissance -- Italy -- Study and teaching (Higher); Jewish refugees -- United States -- Correspondence; Bouwsma, William J. (William James), 1923-2004; Brucker, Gene A.; Baron, Hans, 1900-; Petrarca, Francesco, 1304-1374; Witt, Ronald G.; Kristeller, Paul Oskar, 1905-1999; Bruni, Leonardo, 1369-1444; Machiavelli, Niccolò, 1469-1527; Fiano, Francesco da, d. 1421
- Hans Baron Papers, 1920-1980, 18 boxes
  Arrangement note
  Materials have been boxed as received and, for the most part, original file folder titles have been retained.
  - Reformation course (Box 1)
  - Ptolemy of Lucca (Box 1)
  - High Renaissance in Italy (Box 1)
  - Original Humanism book beginning with Cicero (Box 1)
  - Vergerio (Box 1)
  - Huldrych Hoch: Sendung Roms Bei Livins (Box 1)
  - The Medieval Emergence of the European Nations, 1000-1300 (Box 2)
  - German Crisis II (Box 2)
  - Renaissance and Reformation (winter 1924/1925) (Box 2)
  - Ancient History course (Box 2)
  - The Ancient Orient (First Half) - Extracts (Box 2)
  - The Greek World from 800 to Hellenism - Extracts (Box 2)
  - Fruhe A... (Box 2)
  - Medieval Course--I. The Foundations of the Middle Ages (Box 2)
  - [Renaissance Liberty] (Box 2)
  - Dragmalogia - Memorandum Rerum Liber (Box 2)
  - Querelle - book manuscript (Box 2)
  - 6 volumes [course notes?] (Box 3-3A)
  - Dialoghi (Box 3-3A)
  - Harvard correspondence (Box 3-3A)
  - Cambridge and Harvard (Box 3-3A)
  - Altere Fassungen... Anti-Bertalot Kritik (Box 3-3A)
  - Theologia poetarum III (Box 3-3A)
  - Bruni (Box 3-3A)
  - Bruni's Okonomik (Box 4)
  - Laudatio (Box 4)
  - Discussions with Mr. Berlin 1979 (Box 4)
  - Luiso's and Berklot's correspondence (Box 4)
  - Correspondence (Box 4)
  - David Herlihy, James Hankins, Gordon Griffiths, Newberry, Ron Witt, Steven Ozment (Box 5)
  - Secretum: Successive Mss. (Box 5)
  - Reviews of the "Crisis of the Early Italian Renaissance" (Box 5)
  - From Petrarch to Bruni (Box 5)
  - Secretum: Preparations (Box 5)
  - Older correspondence [1960's, 1970's] (Box 6-6A)
  - Festschrift letters (Box 6-6A)
  - Secretum: Preparations (Box 6-6A)
  - German Crisis (Box 6-6A)
  - Search Additions (Box 6-6A)
  - Habilitationsschrift und Plane in England (Box 7)
  - From planned volumes of political texts (Box 7)
  - Nesi, De Moribus (Box 7)
  - Poggio, De vera nobilitate (Box 7)
  - Survey and chronology of planned editions (Box 7)
  - J. Kirshner (Box 7)
  - Material for further Bruni editions (Box 7)
  - Material and drafts for new Boccaccio chapter (Box 7)
  - First visiting lectures in America (Box 8)
  - Harvard course (Box 8)
  - Search: Addenda (Box 8)
  - Secretum: Additions (Box 8)
  - Institute for Research in the Humanitites, Madison, Wisconsin/Columbia University (Box 8)
  - Secretum: Preparations (Box 8)
  - Dartmouth (Box 9)
  - Studies in Newberry manuscripts (Box 9)
  - Notes, 1920s (title supplied by archivist) (Box 9)
  - Lesefruchte aus Privatdozenten-Zeit (Box 9)
  - Cato Cepaludemus (Box 9)
  - Recent correspondence from Philadelphia trip, 1960's, 3 folders (Box 9A)
  - Correspondence - "Northeast except for Harvard," 1944-1969, 2 folders (Box 9A)
  - Josef Soudek (Box 9A)
  - Kristeller (Box 9A)
  - Lammers (Box 9A)
  - Correspondence (Box 10)
    Scope and Contents note
    Individuals and subjects include: Donald Weinstein, Marvin Becker, Gene A. Brucker, Garrett Mattingly, Droz, Grendler, Pennsylvania and Southeast, Middle West and Canada, Valeri, Cervani, Sasso, Garin, Pieri, Chabod, Far West, Italy
  - Photostats, microforms (Box 10)
  - Photostats (Box 11)
  - Tax records (1968-1969) (Box 11)
  - Bruni material (Box 11)
  - Bertalet (Box 11)
  - Colloquium (Chicago) (Box 11)
  - Bruni (Second Part, Chap. 2) (Box 12-12A)
  - Theologia Poetarum (Box 12-12A)
  - Florence and Humanism (Box 12-12A)
  - Chicago colloquium (Box 12-12A)
  - Petrarch: Inner Struggles (Box 12-12A)
  - Venetian letters (Box 12-12A)
  - Medieval Background and Petrarch (Box 12-12A)
  - Bertalot (Box 12-12A)
  - Zweiter Teil (Box 13)
  - Bruni, birth date (Box 13)
  - Correspondence with Witt (Box 13)
  - Bruni material (Box 13)
  - John Najemy (Box 13)
  - Denys Hay (Box 13)
  - Theologia Poetarum (Box 14)
  - Medieval Capitalism (Box 14)
  - Harvard correspondence (Box 14)
  - Franciscan Poverty, Petrarch, and Trecento (Box 14)
  - Bruni: Phases (chronology of Bruni's writings) (Box 14)
  - Bruni: Materials [including printed works] (Box 14)
  - Preparations for 1969 address on the Principe (Box 14)
  - Beginning of 1974 Machiavelli ms. (Box 14)
  - Ermete Rossi (1927) (Box 14)
  - Stoicism and lay spirit (Box 14)
  - Chap. 26 as supposed key to the Prince in early 19th century (Box 15)
  - Marsilius of Padua (Box 15)
  - Occam and Franciscan Spirituals (Box 15)
  - Conciliar Movement (Columbus seminar) (Box 15)
  - Appendix to Seminar on late-medieval political thought: The Problems of Lay Religiosity and Heresy (Box 15)
  - Appendix Staatsanschauungen des Spat-Mittelalters (Box 15)
  - More and Erasmus (Box 15)
  - Machiavelli and Guicciardini (Box 15)
  - First bibliographical collection for a planned research review on Erasmus (Box 15)
  - Civil humanism - sociological interpretation (Box 15)
  - Petrarch (Box 15)
  - From Universal Empire file (Box 15)
  - Franciscan Poverty (Box 16)
  - Gini Corti Lewis Bateman (Box 16)
  - Bruni (Box 16)
  - Rediscovery of Medieval Classical Tradition, and the Humanistic Culture of the Renaissance (Box 16)
  - Paris - Oxford Science; Realism in Renaissance (Box 16)
  - Education in Renaissance (Box 16)
  - Education in Renaissance Political-Historical Thought and 15th-century historiography (Box 16)
  - Joanna Hitchcock (Box 16)
  - Renaissance seminar (Box 16)
  - (Political thought...) (Box 17)
  - Humanism and ideas of citizenship (Box 17)
  - Quest for citizen-army (Box 17)
  - Petrarch (Box 17)
  - In search of Florentine Civic Humanism (Box 17)
  - Photostats - Salutati (Box 17)
  - Caesar or Cato? (Box 17)
  - England and Austria [ correspondence] (Box 17)
  - Toward a more positive... (Box 17)
  - Bruni youth - chronology (Box 17)
  - Concept of "Civic Humanism" (Box 18)
  - Florentine liberty (Box 18)
  - Studies in Medieval and Renaissance History (Box 18)
  - Hugo Jaeckel (Box 18)
  - Simeoni and Valeri (Box 18)
  - Domenico Maffei (Box 18)
  - Old preparations for footnotes of Crisis (Box 18)
  - Machiavelli (Box 18)
  - Burckhardt (Box 19)
  - Political growth of Renaissance Italy (Box 19)
  - [Reviews, articles, and correspondence concerning them] (Box 19)
  - First courses in America (Box 19)
  - Imperical cities during the Reformation (Box 20)
  - Palmieri: Paper and chronology; Cambi: Criticism (Box 20)
  - Economic history - Course I and II (Box 20)
  - Bibliography and Auxiliary sciences (Box 20)
  - Humanism and the Problem of "Vita activa" in Antiquity and in the Middle Ages (Box 20)
  - Reformation and Political Thought (Box 20)
  - Alamanno Rinuccini "De Libertate" (Box 21)
  - Renaissance auxiliary sciences, libraries-archives (Box 21)
  - Machiavelli in the modern world (Box 21)
  - Balance-of-Power idea in the modern world (Box 21)
  - Reformation and Political Thought (Box 21)
  - Ptolemy of Lucca, criticism (Box 21)
  - German humanism, geographical (Box 21)
  - Crisis, 3rd edition (Box 22)
  - Fifteenth Century, Cambridge chapter (Box 22)
  - Historiography in Italy (Box 22)
  - America, History and Literature (Box 22)
  - America and Historical Science (Box 22)
  - Historiography outside America and Italy (Box 22)
  - Vorlesungen in Berlin (Box 22)
  - Collections for "Querelle" Papers (Box 23)
  - Judaica - Christian movements of today (Box 23)
  - Political and Economic history of modern epoch (Box 23)
  - Extracts for Gellins Paper (Box 23)
  - Glory and Passion (Box 23)
  - Astrology (first collections) (Box 23)
  - Civilization of the 18th and 19th centuries (Box 23)
  - Contemporary (Box 23)
  - Anthropology (Box 23)
  - Literaturegeschichte (Box 23)
  - Reprinting Crisis (Box 23)
  - Italian Bibliography: A-Ci, Co-L, M-R, S-Z (Box 24)
  - Erasmus (Box 24)
  - M.A. Allf: Polit... (Box 24)
  - Renaissance humanism in England, Netherlands, East Europe (Box 24)
  - Historical Thought in Middle Ages (Box 25)
  - German humanists (Box 25)
  - Historical Thought in Antiquity and Islam (Box 25)
  - Savonarola and Platonism in Florence (Box 25)
  - Influence of Flor. Platonism and Civil Humanism on the North (Box 26)
  - Ficino-Colet Erasmus (Box 26)
  - 16th century outside Florence (Box 26)
  - Renaissance and humanism in France and Spain/Portugal (Box 26)
  - Historiography--general and modern (Box 26)
  - Discoveries; politics and economics of 16th century; Reformers (Box 26)
  - Polit. and Verlass.-Gesch. Italiens, M.A. and Renaiss. (Box 27)
  - Counter Reformation, Classicism and Baroque (Box 27)
  - Culture of the Middle Ages (Box 27)
  - Vorgeschichte - Antike (Box 28)
  - Mittelalter, politisch, ...1300 (Box 28)
  - Petrarch, Hum, des Trecento (Box 28)
  - 14th century in Florence (Box 28)
  - New Background I, II, III, IV (Box 29-32)
  - Political, Social, Economic (Box 33-38)
  - City State (Box 39-40)
  - Civic Hum, Ideas, Vita activa and political humanism (Box 41-42)
  - Machiavelli (Box 43-49)
  - Petrarch (Box 50-54)
  - Ptolemy to Petrarch, etc. (Box 55)
  - Modern Mind (Box 56-57)
  - Discovering (Box 58-62)
  - Bruni (Box 63-65)
- Accession (1995-0028), 6 boxes
  - The Everlasting Empire (Box 1)
  - The School of Petrarch and Late Trecento (Box 1)
  - Dante (Box 1)
  - Renaissance Scholarship (Box 2)
  - Music in the Renaissance (Box 2)
  - Aldo Scaglione (Box 2)
  - Education (Box 2)
  - Querelle des Anciens et des Modernes (Box 2)
  - Petrarch (Box 2)
  - Petrarch (Box 3)
  - Ilardi (Box 3)
  - Renaissance scholarship (Box 3)
  - History of law (Box 3)
  - Writings of Guido Kisch (Box 3)
  - Writings and correspondence from other scholars--Ronald Witt, William Bouwsma, et al. (Box 4)
  - Writings and correspondence from other scholars--Donald Kelley, Oskar Kristeller, et al. (Box 5)
  - In search of Florentine civic humanism: essays on the transition from medieval to modern thought--early and late preparation (Box 6)
- Accession (1998-0091), 1 folder
  Addition (98-091) (17 items, .1 lin. ft.; dated 1954-1986) contains primarily letters to Baron regarding publications in his specialty, and well as his notes on pulications and letters to authors. This material is housed with Acc. 2008-0144 (Box 1).
  - Accession (1998-0091) (Box 1)
- Accession (2002-0265), 1 Box
  Addition (02-265) (200 items, .4 lin. ft.; dated 1928-1971) contains research notes and materials relating to Francesco da Fiano, a 15th century Italian humanist. Also includes a packet of correspondence between Gene Brucker and Baron (1961-1971).
  - Accession (2002-0265) (Box 1)
- Accession (2008-0144), 1 folder
  Addition (08-144) (45 items, .1 lin. ft.; dated 1971-1988) primarily contains correspondence between Baron and Ronald Witt regarding their publications and research, including grants for release time and negotiations with publishers; their agreements and disagreements regarding their area of specialization; and the problems associated with teaching at the college level in their specialty. Includes a few addendums to letters written by Baron's wife, Edith, as well as two letters to Witt from other sources. A few of the letters are missing pages.
  - Accession (2008-0144) (Box 1)
- Accession (2012-0112), 2 boxes
  Addition (2012-112) (0.8 lin. ft., 600 items) includes notes and edited drafts related to Hans Baron's work on Leonardo Bruni.
  - Chapter I - edited draft (Box 1)
  - Chapter I - edited draft (Box 1)
  - Chapter I - edited draft (Box 1)
  - Chapter II - edited draft (Box 1)
  - Chapter II - additional text (Box 1)
  - Chapter II - edited draft (Box 1)
  - Chapter II - addenda draft (Box 1)
  - Chapter III - notes and edited draft (Box 1)
  - The importance of the events of 1412 (Box 1)
  - Chapter IV - edited draft (Box 1)
  - Chapter V - edited draft (Box 2)
  - Chapter VI - notes and edited draft (Box 2)
  - Chapter VI - notes and edited draft (Box 2)
  - Chapter VII - edited draft (Box 2)
  - Unknown chapter - edited draft (Box 2)
  - Chapter VIII - edited draft (Box 2)
- Accession (2015-0108), 6.0 Linear Feet
  Scope and Contents
  Personal and academic correspondence and other papers, largely dating from the 1930s and 1940s, written in English and German. Correspondence includes telegrams, manuscript letters, and typescripts, and has been loosely arranged by year.
  - Research, Teaching, Travel, Notes, and Official Documents, 1903-1969; 2
    - Hilfsdienst (emergency service WWI), 1917-1918 (Box Acc. 15/108: Box 4)
    - Habilitation, 1927-1929, undated (Box Acc. 15/108: Box 4)
    - Switzerland, 1933-1935 (Box Acc. 15/108: Box 4)
      Includes correspondence with the "Notgemeinschaft deutscher Wissenschaftler im Ausland" (Emergency Committee in Aid of Displaced Foreign Scholars), Applications to Swiss Universities, and documents regarding "Umhabilitierung" (licensing to teach as a tenured professor in Switzerland).
    - Italy (Florence, Rome, Turin, Bologna, Milan, Padua, Venice, Pisa), 1924-1936 (Box Acc. 15/108: Box 4)
      File of correspondence from scholars and acquaintances, receipts, and many notes includes a 9-page bundle of travel notes in German, written while in Rome and dated July 1925, expressing the happiness of the period he spent in Florence, and comparing Florentine culture, art and architecture, and historical sites to those of Rome (accession 2016-0218). Three dots prefacing these notes appear to be a continuation of another travel essay.
    - Italy and Notgemeinschaft der deutschen Wissenschaft (Emergency Association of German Science), 1925-1927 (Box Acc. 15/108: Box 4)
    - Jews in [Fascits] Italy, Jewish Organizations, 1934, undated (Box Acc. 15/108: Box 4)
    - Expenses for the Historical Commission Munich, 1928-1929, undated (Box Acc. 15/108: Box 4)
    - University of Munich, 1929-1932 (Box Acc. 15/108: Box 4)
    - University of Berlin, 1931-1932 (Box Acc. 15/108: Box 4)
    - Tax Documents (Berlin), 1936-1937 (Box Acc. 15/108: Box 4)
    - Tax Documents (Jewish Community Berlin), 1931-1934 (Box Acc. 15/108: Box 4)
    - Move to US, 1938, undated (Box Acc. 15/108: Box 4)
      Includes inventory list of household items and Baron's personal library.
    - Queens College, New York (Teaching), 1940-1942, undated (Box Acc. 15/108: Box 4)
    - John Hopkins University (Teaching), 1946-1947, undated (Box Acc. 15/108: Box 4)
    - University of Chicago (Teaching), 1963-1969; 2 folders (Box Acc. 15/108: Box 4)
    - Columbia University, 1939-1949 (Box Acc. 15/108: Box 4)
    - Grant Applications to Guggenheim Foundation and American Philosophical Society, 1941-1944 (Box Acc. 15/108: Box 4)
    - Deutsche Wiedergutmachung (German Restitution), 1951-1964 (Box Acc. 15/108: Box 4)
    - Official Documents, ca. 1906-1935, undated; 2 folders (Box Acc. 15/108: Box 4)
      Includes school report cards, high school graduation certificate (Reifezeugnis), univerity diplomas, marriage license, birth certificate, genealogical documents, etc.
    - Miscellaneous Documents, undated (Box Acc. 15/108: Box 4)
      Includes newspaper clippings, single articles, bank statements, various receipts, notes on (mainly American) scholars, etc.
    - Official Documents and Letters (Edith Baron), ca. 1903-1938, undated (Box Acc. 15/108: Box 4)
      Includes ID cards, high school graduation certificate (Reifezeugnis), univerity diplomas, dissertation documents, articles by Edith Baron, some letters, etc.
  - Correspondence, 1867-1969 and undated; 1
    - General correspondence, 1867-1869, 1892, 1914, 1926, 1928-1942; 29 folders (Box Acc. 15/108: Box 1)
      Most of the letters from 1867-1869 are signed by a David and sent from Breslau (Wroclav).
    - General correspondence, 1943-1969; 34 folders (Box Acc. 15/108: Box 2)
    - Jewish Economic Aid, Oldenbourg Pusblishing House, German CVs, 1933-1934 (Box Acc. 15/108: Box 3)
      Includes correspondence with Friedrich Meinecke (Berlin) and the publishing house Oldenbourg regarding the referral of a contribution to a handbook on the Renaissance to Prof. Goetz and future carreer plans.
    - England (1935-1937), Documents and Letters, 3 folders (Box Acc. 15/108: Box 3)
    - Search for position in the U.S., 1938-1948; 7 folders (Box Acc. 15/108: Box 3)
    - Queens College, New York, 1942-1943 (Box Acc. 15/108: Box 3)
    - John Hopkins University, 1946-1950, 1953 (Box Acc. 15/108: Box 3)
    - American Council of Learned Societies, 1941-1947, undated (Box Acc. 15/108: Box 3)
    - Bollingen Foundation, 1946-1948, undated (Box Acc. 15/108: Box 3)
    - Guggenheim Foundation (Fellowship Application), 1941-1948 (Box Acc. 15/108: Box 3)
    - Historische Kommission der Wissenschaften, Munchen (Historical Commission of the Sciences, Munich), 1928-1934; 2 folders (Box Acc. 15/108: Box 3)
    - Else Staudinger (American Committee for Scholars, Writers, and Artists), the Marion R. Ascoli Fund, the New School for Social Research, and the Emergency Committee, 1943-1948 (Box Acc. 15/108: Box 3)
    - American Philosophical Society, 1943-1948 (Box Acc. 15/108: Box 3)
    - The Institute for Advanced Study, Princetion, NJ, 1944-1948 (Box Acc. 15/108: Box 3)
    - Sweden and Denmark, 1934-1935 (Box Acc. 15/108: Box 3)
      Regarding financial support for his Renaissance studies.
    - D. C. Allen (John Hopkins), 1946 (Box Acc. 15/108: Box 3)
    - Fritz Epstein, 1938-1944 (Box Acc. 15/108: Box 3)
    - Walter Goetz, 1947-1959 (Box Acc. 15/108: Box 3)
    - Edith Lenel, 1956-1969 (Box Acc. 15/108: Box 4)
    - Bodo Richter, 1956-1967 (Box Acc. 15/108: Box 4)
    - Harry Starr, 1948 (Box Acc. 15/108: Box 4)
    - Undated Letters, 2 folders (Box Acc. 15/108: Box 4)
    - Letter Fragments, 1937, 1943, 1946, 1947, undated (Box Acc. 15/108: Box 4)
- Accession (2017-0111, 2018-0017, and 2018-0080), 1952-2018 and undated; 0.2 Linear Feet 3 folders
  - Poggio Florentini, 1952-1969 and undated (Box Acc. 17/111-18/080: Box 1)
    Includes reproductions from the Newberry Library, manuscript drafts written in German and Latin, and correspondence.
  - William Bouwsma, 1954-2004 (Box Acc. 17/111-18/080: Box 1)
    Correspondence to Professor William J. Bouwsma.
  - Correspondence, 1960-2018 (Box Acc. 17/111-18/080: Box 1)